<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="addon">
  <id>org.gimp.GIMP.Plugin.GMic</id>
  <extends>org.gimp.GIMP</extends>
  <name>G'MIC</name>
  <summary>GREYC's Magic for Image Computing</summary>
  <url type="homepage">https://gmic.eu/</url>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>CECILL-C</project_license>
  <updatecontact>hub_AT_figuiere.net</updatecontact>
  <releases>
    <release date="2020-09-03" version="2.9.2">
      <description>
        <p>New features</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New plug-in filter Artistic / Doodle creates doodles from input photographs.</li>
          <li>
            New native command mproj (stands for matrix projection)
            computes the projection of a matrix into a prescribed
            dictionnary (defined as another matrix), with the choice
            of various projection methods : ortho-projection, matching
            pursuit, and orthogonal matching pursuit. Useful stuff for
            sparse dictionnary learning. Math evaluator gets an
            equivalent mproj() function as well.
          </li>
          <li>
            New pre-defined variables in and in#ind return the L2-norm
            of respectively current image and image #ind, viewed as
            vectors or matrices (in that case, the Frobenius
            norm). Corresponding function in(_#ind) does the same for
            images with dynamic content (e.g. images under
            modification).
          </li>
          <li>
            New commands xyz2jzazbz, rgb2jzazbz, jzazbz2xyz and
            jzazbz2rgb convert RGB or XYZ colors to the Jzazbz
            colorspace (and vice-versa). Code for these commands has
            been borrowed from this page 2 by Alan Gibson (@snibgo).
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Improvements / Modifications</p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Remove support for deprecated double-hyphen prefix
            (--command). Use +command instead.
          </li>
          <li>
            A few internal functions for matrix calculus have been
            better parallelized, when applied on large matrices
            (multiplication, norm, dot product, …).
          </li>
          <li>
            Command invert accepts an optional argument to choose
            between different solver for matrix inversion (can be
            0=SVD or 1=LU). SVD solver is slower for large matrices,
            but less numerically instable. Math evaluator functions
            invert() and pseudoinvert() also gets this optional
            argument.
          </li>
          <li>
            Commands fill and eval better manage auto- or forced
            parallelization when image has a few columns.
          </li>
          <li>
            Commands solve, invert, svd, trisolve and blur : use
            double precision for computation.
          </li>
          <li>
            Command object3d: Add modification in a 3D object format
            to define a perfect sphere primitive from a pair
            (center,point), rather than specifying it only with its
            diameter (point1,point2).
          </li>
          <li>
            Command +echo is now implemented as a native command (faster).
          </li>
          <li>
            Command echo better manages messages starting with CR character.
          </li>
          <li>
            Commands discard and split : When possible, preserve
            principal axis of processed images.
          </li>
          <li>
            Command label: Change output behavior in order to manage
            multi-channels input images, and output always a
            single-channel label image even when a multi-spectral
            input image is given.
          </li>
          <li>
            Command label: New argument to choose between L1 and
            L2-norms for tolerance comparisons.
          </li>
          <li>
            Function transp(), inv() and pseudoinv() have been renamed
            respectively as transpose(), invert() and pseudoinvert()
            to be more coherent with the name of the corresponding
            pipeline commands.
          </li>
          <li>
            Remove useless command unrepeat (eq. to discard without arguments).
          </li>
          <li>
            Add illuminant E as a possible choice for color conversion
            commands involving the XYZ colorspace. Set it as default
            illuminant when no explicit illuminant is specified.
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bugfix</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Math evaluator: Fix possibly wrong pointer in call to delete.</li>
          <li>Command solve: Fix compilation issue when Lapack support is enabled.</li>
          <li>Filter Apply External CLUT: Implement Strength control.</li>
          <li>Fix command colormap, for some degenerated cases.</li>
          <li>Fix possible canvas shift when applying a filter inside a selection.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-06-10" version="2.9.1"/>
  </releases>
​</component>
